try { const e = document.querySelector(".start_btn button"), t = document.querySelector(".info_box"), o = t.querySelector(".buttons .quit"), n = (t.querySelector(".buttons .restart"), document.querySelector(".quiz_box")), s = document.querySelector(".result_box"), a = document.querySelector(".option_list"), r = document.querySelector("header .time_line"), l = document.querySelector(".timer .time_left_txt"), c = document.querySelector(".timer .timer_sec"); let u; function selectCat(e) { u = e, t.classList.remove("activeInfo"), n.classList.add("activeQuiz"), showQuetions(0), queCounter(1), startTimer(15), startTimerLine(0) } e.onclick = (() => { t.classList.add("activeInfo"), $("#ready-text").hide() }), o.onclick = (() => { t.classList.remove("activeInfo"), $("#ready-text").show() }); let d, h, f = 15, p = 0, m = 1, b = 0, g = 0; const v = s.querySelector(".buttons .restart"), w = s.querySelector(".buttons .quit"); v.onclick = (() => { n.classList.add("activeQuiz"), s.classList.remove("activeResult"), f = 15, m = 1, b = 0, g = 0, showQuetions(p = 0), queCounter(m), clearInterval(d), clearInterval(h), startTimer(f), startTimerLine(g), l.textContent = "Time Left", y.classList.remove("show") }), w.onclick = (() => { window.location.reload() }); const y = document.querySelector("footer .next_btn"), q = document.querySelector("footer .total_que"); function showQuetions(e) { const t = document.querySelector(".que_text"); let o = "<span>" + questions[u][e].numb + ". " + questions[u][e].question + "</span>", n = '<div class="option"><span>' + questions[u][e].options[0] + '</span></div><div class="option"><span>' + questions[u][e].options[1] + '</span></div><div class="option"><span>' + questions[u][e].options[2] + '</span></div><div class="option"><span>' + questions[u][e].options[3] + "</span></div>"; t.innerHTML = o, a.innerHTML = n; const s = a.querySelectorAll(".option"); for (i = 0; i < s.length; i++)s[i].setAttribute("onclick", "optionSelected(this)") } y.onclick = (() => { p < questions[u].length - 1 ? (m++, showQuetions(++p), queCounter(m), clearInterval(d), clearInterval(h), startTimer(f), startTimerLine(g), l.textContent = "Time Left", y.classList.remove("show")) : (clearInterval(d), clearInterval(h), showResult()) }); let A = '<div class="icon tick"><i class="fa fa-check"></i></div>', T = '<div class="icon cross"><i class="fa fa-times"></i></div>'; function optionSelected(e) { clearInterval(d), clearInterval(h); let t = e.textContent, o = questions[u][p].answer; const n = a.children.length; if (t == o) b += 1, e.classList.add("correct"), e.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", A), console.log("Correct Answer"), console.log("Your correct answers = " + b); else for (e.classList.add("incorrect"), e.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", T), console.log("Wrong Answer"), i = 0; i < n; i++)a.children[i].textContent == o && (a.children[i].setAttribute("class", "option correct"), a.children[i].insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", A), console.log("Auto selected correct answer.")); for (i = 0; i < n; i++)a.children[i].classList.add("disabled"); y.classList.add("show") } function showResult() { t.classList.remove("activeInfo"), n.classList.remove("activeQuiz"), s.classList.add("activeResult"); const e = s.querySelector(".score_text"); if (b / questions[u].length >= .75) { let t = "<span>Well done! You got <p>" + b + "</p> out of <p>" + questions[u].length + "</p></span>"; e.innerHTML = t, totalPoints += b, userPoints.innerHTML = parseFloat(totalPoints.toFixed(0)), Storage.savePoint(totalPoints.toFixed(0)) } else if (b / questions[u].length >= .5) { let t = "<span>Nice! You got <p>" + b + "</p> out of <p>" + questions[u].length + "</p></span>"; e.innerHTML = t } else { let t = "<span>Try again! You got only <p>" + b + "</p> out of <p>" + questions[u].length + "</p></span>"; e.innerHTML = t } } function startTimer(e) { d = setInterval(function () { if (c.textContent = e, --e < 9) { let e = c.textContent; c.textContent = "0" + e } if (e < 0) { clearInterval(d), l.textContent = "Time Off"; const e = a.children.length; let t = questions[u][p].answer; for (i = 0; i < e; i++)a.children[i].textContent == t && (a.children[i].setAttribute("class", "option correct"), a.children[i].insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", A), console.log("Time Off: Auto selected correct answer.")); for (i = 0; i < e; i++)a.children[i].classList.add("disabled"); y.classList.add("show") } }, 1e3) } function startTimerLine(e) { if (screen.width < 768) { function t() { e += 1, r.style.width = e + "px", e > 339 && clearInterval(h) } console.log("test1"), h = setInterval(t, 47) } else { function t() { e += 1, r.style.width = e + "px", e > 549 && clearInterval(h) } console.log("test2"), h = setInterval(t, 29) } } function queCounter(e) { let t = "<span><p>" + e + "</p> of <p>" + questions[u].length + "</p> Questions</span>"; q.innerHTML = t } } catch { console.log("This page isn't the quiz page, quiz script will not be executed.") } let questions = { airPollution: [{ numb: 1, question: "Which is the most air polluted country?", answer: "Bangladesh", options: ["Singapore", "Beijing", "Bangladesh", "USA"] }, { numb: 2, question: "What effects of air pollution on the human body?", answer: "All of the above", options: ["Vunerability to infections and diseases", "Damage to reproductive functions", "Increased risk of stroke and dementia", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 3, question: "What are the major causes of air pollution", answer: "All of the above", options: ["Combustion of fossil fuels", "Emissions from vehicles", "Deforestation", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 4, question: "What is an example of a greenhouse gas?", answer: "A and B", options: ["Carbon Monoxide", "Carbon Dioxide", "Oxygen", "A and B"] }, { numb: 5, question: "Which is not a effect of air pollution on the environment?", answer: "Ecosystem remains unchanged", options: ["Climate Change", "Ozone layer gets damaged", "Ecosystem remains unchanged", "Habitats get destroyed"] }], deforestation: [{ numb: 1, question: "What is the estimated annual rate of deforestation?", answer: "1.3 million km2 per decade", options: ["41.7 million km2 per decade", "1.3 billion km2 per decade", "1.3 million km2 per decade", "6.9 million km2 per decade"] }, { numb: 2, question: "Which forest is considered the 'lungs' of the planet?", answer: "The Amazon Rainforest", options: ["The Congo Rainforest", "Daintree Rainforest", "The Amazon Rainforest", "Southeast Asian Rainforest"] }, { numb: 3, question: "Deforestation is the second leading cause of global warming in the world.", answer: "True", options: ["True", "False"] }, { numb: 4, question: "What are the effects of deforestation", answer: "All of the above", options: ["Climate Change", "Loss of Biodiversity", "Food Insecurity", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 5, question: "What can be done to stop deforestation?", answer: "Plant more trees", options: ["Use more paper", "Buy products containing palm oil", "Plant more trees", "All of the above"] }], foodWaste: [{ numb: 1, question: "How many tons of food is wasted each year?", answer: "1.3 billion tons", options: ["50,000 tons", "3 billion tons", "1.3 billion tons", "100,000 tons"] }, { numb: 2, question: "If we produce food that doesnâ€™t get eaten, what else is wasted?", answer: "All of the above", options: ["Wildlife Habitats", "Water", "Energy", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 3, question: "When food waste is sent to landfills, it decomposes to produce what gas more deadly than carbon dioxide?", answer: "Methane", options: ["Oxygen", "Methane", "Carbon Monoxide", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 4, question: "What food when wasted, represents the biggest waste of energy?", answer: "Beef", options: ["Milk", "Poultry", "Corn", "Beef"] }, { numb: 5, question: "What can be done to prevent food waste?", answer: "Donate unsold food", options: ["Donate unsold food", "Throw away more food", "Order more take out", "All of the above"] }], globalWarming: [{ numb: 1, question: "Air pollution is one of the causes of climate change", answer: "True", options: ["True", "False"] }, { numb: 2, question: "What is the greenhouse effect?", answer: "Gases in the atmosphere trapping heat increasing global temperatures", options: ["The name of climate change legislation passed by Congress", "Painting the house green", "Gases in the atmosphere trapping heat increasing global temperatures", "Option 4"] }, { numb: 3, question: "What are the effects of climate change?", answer: "All of the Above", options: ["Increase in global temperatures", "Rising sea levels", "Loss in biodiversity", "All of the Above"] }, { numb: 4, question: "When are sea levels predicted to rise between 1 and 2.3 feet?", answer: "2050", options: ["2043", "2050", "2078", "2100"] }, { numb: 5, question: "What can we do to stop climate change?", answer: "Walk, cycle or take public transport", options: ["Eat less vegetables", "Throw away more food", "Walk, cycle or take public transport", "All of the above"] }], lossOfBiodiversity: [{ numb: 1, question: "How does loss of biodiversity affect us?", answer: "Decrease our ability to produce medicine", options: ["Provides us with more food", "Protects us against natural disasters", "Decrease our ability to produce medicine", "Loss of biodiversity does not affect humans"] }, { numb: 2, question: "Which land-based ecosystem has the most biodiversity", answer: "Tropical Rainforests", options: ["Deserts", "Tropical Rainforests", "Tundras", "Grasslands"] }, { numb: 3, question: "What are the causes of loss of biodiversity?", answer: "All of the Above", options: ["Pollution", "Climate Change", "Human Activity", "All of the Above"] }, { numb: 4, question: "The status of a 'threatened species' means:", answer: "they are likely to become endangered", options: ["they are almost extinct", "they are likely to become endangered", "they are extinct", "their numbers are increasing"] }, { numb: 5, question: "Which of the following is not a type of biodiversity", answer: "Individual", options: ["Species", "Genetic", "Ecosystem", "Individual"] }], plasticPollution: [{ numb: 1, question: "How many million tons of plastic are dumped in our oceans every year?", answer: "8 million tons", options: ["1 million tons", "8 million tons", "20 million tons", "50 million tons"] }, { numb: 2, question: "Single-use plastic accounts for ___% of the plastic produced each year", answer: "40", options: ["5", "10", "25", "40"] }, { numb: 3, question: "What happens to plastic waste left in the environment?", answer: "It never fully goes away, it breaks into little pieces", options: ["It is biodegradable so it eventually disintegrates", "It never fully goes away, it breaks into little pieces", "There is no such things as plastic waste as they are all recycled"] }, { numb: 4, question: "Why is plastic dangerous for marine life", answer: "All of the above", options: ["They mistake it for food and cannot digest it", "They get tangled in it which hinders their movement", "Bacteria on plastic can give coral diseases", "All of the above"] }, { numb: 5, question: "What can we do to stop plastic pollution?", answer: "Bring your own reusable bag", options: ["Buy more plastic water bottles", "Order more takeout", "Purchase brand new items", "Bring your own reusable bag"] }] };